

IYANU HENRY FAMORITIYE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

I am a passionate and driven software engineer with a deep love for technology and a strong desire to create innovative solutions. My journey in the world of software development has been a thrilling adventure marked by constant learning and growth. My technical expertise encompasses a wide range of programming languages, including HTML, CSS and JavaScript but not limited to other object oriented languages. I am well-versed in the entire software development lifecycle, from conceptualization to implementation, testing, and maintenance. I have a strong command of software design principles and a passion for writing clean, efficient code.

CONTACT

PHONE: +234 81 666 733 25

LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/henryfamoritiye

EMAIL:

Henry.famoritive@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Moshhod Abiola Polytechnic Higher National Diploma

October 2014 – October 2020 GPA: 3.04

Suncity College Secondary Education

2008 - 2014

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tony Elumelu Foundation Front-end Engineer Internship 2017–2018

- Assisted in the development and maintenance of front-end web application, resulting in positive impact on the company's overall performance
- Granted additional code review permission after demonstrating strong attention to details that led to a 25% decrease in code errors.
- Provide support to senior front-end developers after becoming proficient in ReactJS, resulting in a stronger, more efficient tech Team.
- Developed and executed front-end development strategies, resulting in a 15% increase in website performance.

H DINTERIEUR Fronte 2021- 2022

Frontend Developer

- Developed and optimized responsive, accessible front-end interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Designed and implemented user-friendly web components to improve the user experience for web applications
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate front-end features with backend systems and databases.
- Delivered front-end solutions that met project goals and supported overall application performance and usability.

LANGUAGE

ENGLISH (Professional) YORUBA (native)

CERTIFICATION

Scrum Fundamentals June 14,2023 Agile fundamentals VEdu.inc

Six Sigma Yellow Belt June 24,2023 Project management VEdu.inc

Introduction to DevOps June 28,2023 IBM Skill Network COUSERA

Introduction to Cloud JULY 18, 2023 IBM Skill Network COUSERA

Front-end Development AUG 08 ,2023 Training by josh UDEMY

React Intermediate Dev Sept 12 ,2024 KODEKAMP

SKILLS

- Web Development
- Technical Support
- Expert in HTML/CSS/JAVASCRIPT
- Technical Writing
- Object Oriented Design
- Proficient with JavaScript and Typescript
- Website Maintenance
- Technical Analysis
- Software Delivery Coordination
- Code Debugging
- Knowledge in UI/UX Design
- Understanding of SEO and security base practice

- Project Management
- Design validation
- Web Trend
- Technical Presentation
- Scripting
- Troubleshooting
- Web Updating
- Front-end Developer React JS
- Web Update
- User Experience
- Knowledge on Git and SVN
- Ability to create unit test for web application
- Familiarity with Agile and Scrum processes.

KEY ACHIEVEMENT

Performance Optimization

Develop and execute front-end development strategies, resulting in a 15% increase in website performance by implementing optimization technique such as

OMINI FOOD AI

I Develop an Al base food ordering platform that focuses on helping people eat well. This might lead to a poor diet and lasting health consequences. We want to solve this problem by using an Al-centric approach. Users can use our app to select their diet and foods they like and dislike, and our Al algorithm will create a custom and individual weekly meal plan. But we don't stop there. We partner with restaurants and other cooking partners to actually cook and deliver all meals from the generated meal plans, in selected cities.